Inventory of the John B. Dunlop collection
Hoover Institution Archives
John B. Dunlop collection
1967-2015
81010
Hoover Institution Archives
226 cubic foot boxes (226 linear feet)
Clippings and other printed matter, relating to the disintegration of the Soviet Union, and to political conditions in post-Soviet Russia. Includes a 1968 official Soviet report (incomplete), summarizing results of the investigation of the Vserossiiskii sotsial-khristianskii soiuz osvobozhdeniia naroda, an anti-communist revolutionary organization in the Soviet Union.
Dunlop, John B., collector.
Access
Collection is open for research. Collection stored off site. It may be possible to have a limited number of boxes brought to the archives reading room for examination. A minimum of two days notice is required. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981 with numerous additional increments through the year 2015.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Clippings and other printed matter, relating to the disintegration of the Soviet Union, and to political conditions in post-Soviet Russia. Includes a 1968 official Soviet report (incomplete), summarizing results of the investigation of the Vserossiiskii sotsial-khristianskii soiuz osvobozhdeniia naroda, an anti-communist revolutionary organization in the Soviet Union.
Arrangement
Arranged in groups by chronological additions to the collection. Most increments are in alphabetical order.
Vserossiiskii sotsial-khristianskii soiuz osvobozhdeniia naroda.; Anti-communist movements--Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation)--Politics and government--1991-; Soviet Union--Politics and government--1985-1991.
- Vserossiiskii sotsial-khristianskii soiuz osvobozhdeniia naroda. Official Soviet report (incomplete), summarizing results of the investigation of the Vserossiiskii sotsial-khristianskii soiuz osvobodzhdeniia naroda, an anti-communist revolutionary organization in the Soviet Union, 1968 (Box 1)
- Baltics, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Baltics, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- Coup, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Coup, 1991 (Box 1)
- Coup, 1991 (Box 2)
- Coup aftermath, 1991 (Box 2)
- Coup aftermath, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- Coup (new), 1992 (Box 2)
- Coup (new), 1992-1994 (Box 2)
- Next coup, 1991-1996 (Box 2)
- Post-coup Union, 1991 (Box 2)
- Post-coup Union, 1991 (Box 3)
- Slavic Commonwealth, 1991 (Box 3)
- Yeltsin, Boris, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
- Yeltsin, Boris, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- Yeltsin, Boris, 1991 (Box 3)
- Yeltsin, Boris, post-coup, 1991 (Box 4)
- Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, 1990 (Box 4)
- Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
- Union treaty, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
- Ecology, 1988-1994 (Box 4)
- Ecology, 1995-2009 (Box 5)
- Commonwealth of Independent States, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
- Commonwealth of Independent States, 1993-1998 (Box 5)
- Russian constitution, 1993 (Box 5)
- Russian constitution, 1993 (Box 5)
- Foreign affairs, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
- Foreign affairs, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
- Foreign affairs, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
- Foreign affairs, 1996 (Box 6)
- Foreign policy, 1992-2000 (Box 6)
- Foreign policy, 2001-2004 (Box 7)
- Russian Communist Party, 1990-1991 (Communist Party of the Russian Federation) (Box 7)
- Russian compatriots, 2007 (Box 7)
- Russian Congress, 1992 (Box 7)
- Russian Congress, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
- Russian conservatism, 1993-2003 (Box 7)
- Russian banks, 1994 (Box 7)
- Russian banks, 1995-1999 (Box 7)
- Russian borders, 1993-1999 (Box 7)
- Russian bureaucracy, 1993-2006 (Box 7)
- Russian business, 2000-2008 (Box 7)
- RSFSR Bureau, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
- RSFSR laws, 1989 (Box 7)
- RSFSR Writers' Union, 1990 (Union of Russian Writers) (Box 7)
- RSFSR Writers Union, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
- RSFSR Writers Union plenums, 1988 and 1990 (Plenum of the Union of Russian Writers) (Box 8)
- RSFSR People's Deputies, 1989 (Box 8)
- RSFSR Presidency and Congress of People's Deputies, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
- Agreements with other republics, 1990 (Box 8)
- State Council of Russia, 1991 (Box 8)
- Heads of republics, 1991 (Box 8)
- Nationalities question, 1985-1988 (Box 8)
- Nationalities question, 1988-1991 (Box 8)
- Russian crime, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
- Russian crime, 1993-1995 (Box 8)
- Chernomyrdin, Viktor, 1992-1997 (Box 9)
- Soiuz (group), 1990-1991 (Box 9)
- Soiuz chastnykh sobstvennikov, 1990 (Box 9)
- Soiuz dukhovnogo vozdozhreniia, 1989 (Box 9)
- Soiuz nezavsimykh pistalei, 1991 (Box 9)
- Soiuz ob'edinennykh kooperatorov, 1990 (Box 9)
- Soiuz ofitserov, 1992 (Box 9)
- Soiuz potomkov rossiiskogo dvorianstva, 1991 (Box 9)
- Soiuz pravoslavnykh grazhdan, 2003 (Box 9)
- Soiuz predpinimatelei Rossii, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
- Soiuz rossiiskikh gorodov, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
- Soiuz rossiiskogo kupechestva, 1990 (Box 9)
- Soiuz russkikh, 1994 (Box 9)
- Soiuz russkogo naroda, 2004 (Box 9)
- Soiuz vozrozhdeniia Rossii, 1993 (Box 9)
- Solomentsev, M. S., 1987 (Box 9)
- Soloukhin, Vladimir, 1984-2004 (Box 9)
- Kozyrev, Andrei, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
- Kozyrev, Andrei, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
- Russia-what is it? 1989-1993 (Box 9)
- Russia-what is it? 1993-1994 (Box 10)
- Khasbulatov, Ruslan, 1991-1992 (Box 10)
- Khasbulatov, Ruslan, 1993-1995 (Box 10)
- Economic agreement, 1993 (Box 10)
- Economic integration, 1993 (Box 10)
- Economy, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
- Economy, 1991-1994 (Box 10)
- Economy, 1994-1999 (Box 11)
- Demokraticheskaia platforma, 1990 (Box 11)
- Demokraticheskaia platforma, 1990 (Box 11)
- Demokraticheskaia Rossiia, 1990-1995 (Box 11)
- Demokraticheskii forum, 1990 (Box 11)
- Demokraticheskii soiuz, 1990 (Box 11)
- Demokraticheskii vybor, 1993-1996 (Box 11)
- Shakhnazarov, Georgii, 1990-1994 (Box 11)
- Shalamov, Varlam, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
- Shatrov, Mikhail, 1986-1989 (Box 11)
- Shelepin, Aleksandr, 1991 (Box 11)
- Shenin, Oleg, 1991-1994 (Box 11)
- Shevardnadze, Eduard, 1990-1995 (Box 11)
- Russian KGB, 1990-1992 (Box 11)
- Russian KGB, 1993-1996 (Box 12)
- Russian Komsomol, 1989-1994 (Box 12)
- Russian land, 1995 (Box 12)
- Russian language, 1990-2004 (Box 12)
- Poltoranin, Mikhail, 1992-1995 (Box 12)
- Popov, Gavriil, 1988-1995 (Box 12)
- Fateev, Valerii, 1998 (Box 12)
- FBR, 2003 (Box 12)
- Fear, 2000 (Box 12)
- Fed', Nikolai, 1989 (Box 12)
- Federal Assembly, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
- Federal Assembly, 1994-1996 (Box 12)
- Sakharov, Andrei, 1989 (Box 12)
- Sakharov, Andrei, 1990 (Box 13)
- Sarnov, Benedikt, 1989 (Box 13)
- Saudi Arabia, 1999-2008 (Box 13)
- Serbia, 1989-1995 (Box 13)
- Serbia, 1995 (Box 13)
- Barkashov, Aleksandr, 1989-1998 (Box 13)
- Barkashov, Aleksandr, 1998 (Box 13)
- Ziuganov, Gennadii, 1994-1997 (Box 13)
- Ziuganov, Gennadii, 1998 (Box 14)
- Zhirinovskii, Vladimir, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
- Zhirinovskii, Vladimir, 1994-1998 (Box 14)
- Referendum, 1993 (Box 14)
- Referendum, 1993 (Box 14)
- Russian crime, 1995-1996 (Box 14)
- Russian crime, 1997-1998 (Box 15)
- North Ossetia, 1998-2008 (Box 15)
- North Caucasus Military District, 1995-1998 (Box 15)
- Nosov, Evgenii, 1989-2002 (Box 15)
- Novaiia Rossiia, 2003 (Box 15)
- Novgorod, 1997-2002 (Box 15)
- Novocherkassk, 1998 (Box 15)
- Novodvorskaia, Valeriia, 1991-2007 (Box 15)
- Novoe Russkoe Dvorianstvo, 1991 (Box 15)
- Novorossiia (Ukraine), 1990-1991 (Box 15)
- Novorossiisk, 1992-2001 (Box 15)
- Narodnaiia partiia Rossiiskoi Federatsii, 2003 (Box 15)
- Narodno-trudovoi soiuz (NTS), 1991-2000 (Box 15)
- Nuclear issues, 1992-1993 (Box 15)
- Nuclear issues, 1993-1998 (Box 15)
- Starkov, Vladislav, 1989-1998 (Box 15)
- Starodubtsev, Vasilii, 1990-2003 (Box 15)
- Starovoitov, Vasilii, 1997 (Box 15)
- Starovoitova, Galina, 1989-1991 (Box 15)
- Starovoitova, Galina, 1992-1999 (Box 15)
- St. George, 2000 (Box 15)
- St. Petersburg, 1991-1999 (Box 15)
- Stabiliziatsionyi Fond, 2006-2007 (Box 15)
- Stadniuk, Iurii, 1991 (Box 15)
- Stagnation, 2001-2004 (Box 15)
- Stankevich, Sergei, 1990-1994 (Box 15)
- Sovetskaia Rossiia, 1988-1992 (Box 15)
- Sovetskii Voin, 1989 (Box 16)
- Soviet debts, 1998 (Box 16)
- Solov'ev, Vladimir, 1989 (Box 16)
- Space program, 1992-2002 (Box 16)
- SPAG, 2005 (Box 16)
- SPAS, 1991-2007 (Box 16)
- Spetsnaz, 2000-2002 (Box 16)
- Spinmeisters, 2004 (Box 16)
- Sports, 1999-2007 (Box 16)
- Soiuz pravykh sil (SPS), 2000-2008 (Box 16)
- Belarus, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
- Belarus, 1994-1996 (Box 16)
- A, miscellaneous (Box 16)
- Academy of Sciences (Box 16)
- Adamovich, Ales', writer (Box 16)
- Afanas'ev, Iurii, 1988-1995 (Box 16)
- Afanas'ev, Viktor, Academician (Box 16)
- Afghanistan, 1984-1999 (Box 16)
- Afghanistan, 2000-2003 (Box 17)
- Africa (Box 17)
- Aid (Box 17)
- Aitmatov, Chingiz, 1967-1991 (Box 17)
- Akhmadulina, Bella (Box 17)
- Akhmatova, Anna (Box 17)
- Akhromeev, Sergei, Marshal (Box 17)
- Argumenty i fakty, newspaper (Box 17)
- Armenia, 1988-1997 (Box 17)
- Armenia, 1998-2001 (Box 17)
- Astaf'ev, Mikhail (Box 17)
- Astaf'ev, Viktor, 1986-2002 (Box 17)
- Avtorkhanov, Abdurakhman (Box 18)
- Azerbaijan, 1989-1999 (Box 18)
- Borovoi, Konstantin (Box 18)
- Bovin, Aleksandr (Box 18)
- Brezhnev, Leonid, 1982-2007 (Box 18)
- Bukharin, Nikolai (Box 18)
- Burlatskii, Fedor, 1986-1988 (Box 18)
- Burlatskii, Fedor, 1989-1993 (Box 18)
- Bush, George H.W., President, 1989-1992 (Box 18)
- Butenko, Anatolii (Box 18)
- Censorship, 1988-1991 (Box 19)
- Central Asia, 1986-1999 (Box 19)
- Chernenko, Konstantin (Box 19)
- Clinton, Bill, 1993-1995 (Box 19)
- Clinton, Bill, 1996-1997 (Box 19)
- Clinton, Bill, 1998 (Box 20)
- Communist Party, 1986-1992 (Box 20)
- Communist Party, 1992-1995 (Box 20)
- Communist Party, Central Committee Plenum, Sep-89 (Box 20)
- Communist Party, Marxist Platform in the CPSU, 1990-1991 (Box 20)
- Dissolving Parliament, 1993-1994 (Box 20)
- Economics, 1987-1989 (Box 20)
- Economics, 1990-1992 (Box 21)
- Falin, Valentin (Box 21)
- Feminism (Box 21)
- Galanskov, Iurii (Box 21)
- Gdlian - Ivanov, 1989-1992 (Box 21)
- Gilevich, Nil (Box 21)
- Ginzburg, Aleksandr (Box 21)
- Glasnost', 1989 (Box 21)
- Glasnost', 1990-1993 (Box 21)
- Glasnost', 1994-1997 (Box 21)
- Lenin, Vladimir, 1990-1996 (Box 21)
- Lenin, Vladimir, 1997-2009 (Box 22)
- Lenin Prize (Box 22)
- Libya (Box 22)
- Ligachev, Yegor, 1985-2000 (Box 22)
- Likhachev, Dmitrii (Box 22)
- Lisichkin, Vladimir (Box 22)
- Lisichkin, Gennadii (Box 22)
- Literaturnaia gazeta (Box 22)
- Liubimov, Iurii (Box 22)
- Liubimov, Mikhail (Box 22)
- London Club (Box 22)
- Losoto, Elena (Box 22)
- Luchinskii, Petr (Box 22)
- Luk'ianov, Anatolii (Box 22)
- Lukin, Vladimir (Box 22)
- Luzhniki, Moscow (Box 22)
- M, miscellaneous (Box 22)
- Macedonia (Box 22)
- Makashov, Albert, General (Box 22)
- Maksimov, Vladimir, writer (Box 22)
- Malaysia (Box 22)
- Marx, Karl (Box 22)
- Marxist Workers Party, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
- Masherov, Petr (Box 22)
- Masliukov, Iurii (Box 22)
- Masons (Box 22)
- Mazurov, Kirill (Box 22)
- Medecins Sans Frontieres, International aid group (Box 22)
- Medvedev, Roy (Box 22)
- Medvedev, Vadim (Box 22)
- Mexico (Box 22)
- Mezhpartiinyi Informatsionnyi Tsentr (Box 22)
- Middle East (Box 22)
- Migranian, Andranik (Box 22)
- Mikhailov, Aleksandr, writer (Box 22)
- Mikoian, Anastas and Sergo (Box 22)
- Military (Box 22)
- Minzhurenko, Aleksandr (Box 22)
- Moldova, 1989-1997 (Box 22)
- Moldova, 1998-2003 (Box 22)
- Molotov, Viacheslav (Box 23)
- OSCE, 2001-2008 (Box 23)
- Pakistan (Box 23)
- Palestine (Box 23)
- Pan-Caucasus (Box 23)
- Panfilov, Oleg (Box 23)
- Pankin, Boris (Box 23)
- Pan-Turkism (Box 23)
- Paris Club (Box 23)
- Rossiiskoe Narodnoe Sobranie, movement (Box 23)
- Russia, Center (Box 23)
- Russia, Center - Republics, 1990-1991 (Box 23)
- Russia - Kazakhstan, 1992 (Box 23)
- Russia - Minority Republics (Box 23)
- Russia, Referendum, 1995-2003 (Box 23)
- Russia - Ukraine, 1991-1993 (Box 23)
- Russia - Ukraine, 1993-1995 (Box 24)
- Russia - Ukraine, 1996-1997 (Box 24)
- Russian Elections, 1993 (Box 24)
- Russian Elections, 1993-1994 (Box 24)
- Russian Elections, 1994-1995 (Box 25)
- Russian Elections, 1996 (Box 25)
- Russian Elections, 1996-1998 (Box 25)
- Russian provinces, 1995-1998 (Box 26)
- Russian refugees, 1990-1994 (Box 26)
- Russian TV/Radio, 1989-1998 (Box 26)
- Russkii Vestnik, journal (Box 26)
- Russkii Vestnik, newspaper (Box 26)
- Russkoe Natsional'noe Edinstvo (Box 26)
- Russkoe Osvoboditel'noe Dvizhenie (Box 26)
- Russkoe Voskresenie, newspaper (Box 26)
- Russneft' (Box 26)
- Russophobia (Box 26)
- Rutskoi, Aleksandr, 1991-1993 (Box 26)
- Rutskoi, Aleksandr, 1993-1999 (Box 27)
- Rutskoi, Aleksandr, 2000-2001 (Box 27)
- Rutskoi, Aleksandr, et al. (Box 27)
- Rybakov, Iulii (Box 27)
- Rybkin, Ivan, 1994-1997 (Box 27)
- Rybkin, Ivan, 1997-1998 (Box 27)
- Shevardnadze, Eduard, 1991,1996-2000 (Box 27)
- Shevtsov, Ivan, writer (Box 27)
- Shmelev, Nikolai, economist (Box 27)
- Shukshin, Vasilii, writer (Box 27)
- Silk Road (Box 28)
- Singapore (Box 28)
- Slovakia (Box 28)
- Slovenia (Box 28)
- Social Democracy (Box 28)
- Socialism (Box 28)
- Society for Threatened Peoples (Box 28)
- Sociology, 1986-1992 (Box 28)
- Sofronov, Anatolii, playwright (Box 28)
- Soglasie (Box 28)
- Soiuz Nezavisimykh Pisatelei (Box 28)
- Solov'iev, Iurii (Box 28)
- Soros, George (Box 28)
- South Africa (Box 28)
- South Caucasus (Box 28)
- South Central America (Box 28)
- South East Asia (Box 28)
- South Korea (Box 28)
- Sovetskaia Molodezh', newspaper (Box 28)
- Sovetskii Pisatel', publishing house (Box 28)
- Soviet-American International University, Moscow (Box 28)
- Soviet journals, general (Box 28)
- Soviet literature, general (Box 28)
- Soviet Writers' Union, 1986-1991 (Box 28)
- Space Program (Box 28)
- Spain (Box 28)
- Stalin, Iosif 1987-1988 (Box 28)
- Stockholm (Box 28)
- Students (Box 28)
- Sudoplatov, Pavel, General (Box 28)
- Supreme Soviet, USSR, 1989-1992 (Box 28)
- Suslov, Mikhail (Box 28)
- Svetov, Feliks, writer (Box 28)
- Sweden (Box 28)
- Switzerland (Box 28)
- Syria (Box 28)
- Taiwan (Box 28)
- Tajikistan, 1989-1997 (Box 28)
- Technology (Box 28)
- Trotskii, Lev (Box 28)
- Tuleev, Aman (Box 28)
- Turkey, 1991-2005 (Box 29)
- Turkmenistan, 1989-2002 (Box 29)
- Ukraine, 1986-1989 (Box 29)
- Ukraine, 1990-1992 (Box 29)
- Ukraine, 1993-1994 (Box 29)
- Ukraine, 1995-1997 (Box 30)
- Ukraine, 1997-2000 (Box 30)
- Ukraine, 2000-2005 (Box 30)
- Ul'ianov, Mikhail, actor (Box 30)
- UN, 1993-2006 (Box 30)
- Unemployment (Box 30)
- United Arab Emirates (Box 30)
- Uranium (Box 31)
- Uruguay (Box 31)
- USSR, analysis (Box 31)
- Uyghur (Box 31)
- Uzbekistan, 1989 (Box 31)
- Vol'skii, Arkadii, 1992-2006 (Box 31)
- Volunteer Army (Box 31)
- VOOP, society (Box 31)
- VOOPIK, society (Box 31)
- Vorob'ev, Eduard, General (Box 31)
- Voronezhskaia Oblast (Box 31)
- Voronin, Iurii (Box 31)
- Vorontsov, Iulii (Box 31)
- Vorotnikov, Vitalii (Box 31)
- Voshchanov, Pavel (Box 31)
- Voskresenie, newspaper (Box 31)
- Voslenskii, Mikhail (Box 31)
- Voznesenskii, Andrei (Box 31)
- Vozrozhdenie, action (Box 31)
- Vozrozhdenie, association (Box 31)
- Vozrozhdenie, fond (Box 31)
- Vozrozhdenie, party (Box 31)
- Vozrozhdenie Rossii, newspaper (Box 31)
- Vozrozhdenie Rossii, party (Box 31)
- Vrangel', Petr, General (Box 31)
- Vserossiiskii natsional'nyi pravyi tsentr (Box 31)
- Vsemirnyi russkii narodnyi sobor (Box 31)
- Chechnia, 1997-1998 (Box 31)
- Chechnia, 1998 (Box 31)
- Chechnia, 1998 (cont.) (Box 32)
- Chechnia, 2001 (Box 32)
- Chechnia, 2001 (cont.) (Box 32)
- Chechnia, 2001 (cont.) (Box 33)
- Chechnia, 2001-2002 (Box 33)
- Chechnia, 2002 (Box 33)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 34)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 34)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 34)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 35)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 35)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 35)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 36)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 36)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 36)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 37)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 37)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 37)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 38)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 38)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 38)
- Chechnia, 2002 (cont.) (Box 39)
- El'tsin, Boris N., President, 1992 (Box 39)
- El'tsin, Boris N., President, 1992-1993 (Box 39)
- El'tsin, Boris N., President, 1994-1995 (Box 39)
- El'tsin, Boris N., President, 1995-1998 (Box 40)
- Empire, 1990-1997 (Box 40)
- Empire, 1997-2000 (Box 40)
- Empire, 2000-001 (Box 41)
- Empire, 2001-002 (Box 41)
- Fascism, 1991-1992 (Box 41)
- Fascism, 1992-1993 (Box 42)
- Fascism, 1993-1994 (Box 42)
- Fascism, 1995-2001 (Box 42)
- Fascism, 2001-2002 (Box 43)
- Fascism, 2002 (Box 43)
- Fascism, 2002 (cont.) (Box 43)
- Fascism, 2003 (Box 44)
- Fascism, 2004 (Box 44)
- Fascism, 2004-2005 (Box 44)
- Lebed', Aleksandr, 1992-1996 (Box 45)
- Lebed', Aleksandr, 1996-1997 (Box 45)
- Lebed', Aleksandr, 1997-1999 (Box 45)
- Lebed', Aleksandr, 1999-2002 (Box 46)
- Baltics, 1994-2005 (Box 46)
- NATO, 1997-2005 (Box 46)
- Oil industry, 1991-1997 (Box 47)
- Oil industry, 1997 (Box 47)
- Oil industry, 1997-1998 (Box 47)
- Oil industry, 1998-1999 (Box 48)
- Polls, 1989-1992 (Box 48)
- Polls, 1993-1994 (Box 48)
- Polls, 1994-1997 (Box 49)
- Polls, 1997-1999 (Box 49)
- Polls, 1999-2000 (Box 49)
- Polls, 2000-2001 (Box 50)
- Polls, 2001-2002 (Box 50)
- Polls, 2002 (Box 50)
- Polls, 2002-2003 (Box 51)
- Polls, 2003 (Box 51)
- Polls, 2003-2004 (Box 51)
- Polls, 2004-2006 (Box 52)
- Polls, 2006-2007 (Box 52)
- Polls, 2007 (Box 52)
- Regionalism, 1992-1993 (Box 53)
- Regionalism, 1994-1997 (Box 53)
- Regionalism, 1997-1998 (Box 53)
- Regionalism, 1998-1999 (Box 54)
- Russia and other republics, 1990-1992 (Box 54)
- Russia and other republics, 1992-1993 (Box 54)
- Russia and other republics, 1993 (Box 55)
- Russia and other republics, 1993-1994 (Box 55)
- Russian elections, 1999-2000 (Box 55)
- Russian elections, 2000-2001 (Box 56)
- Serbia, 1996-1999 (Box 56)
- Elections, 1990 (Box 56)
- National Salvation committee (Box 56)
- NATO, 1991-1996 (Box 56)
- Nazarbaev, Nursultan (Box 56)
- Nekrason, Viktor (Box 56)
- Nekrich, Aleksandr (Box 56)
- Netherlands (Box 56)
- New World Disorder (Box 56)
- NGO's, 2000-2001 (Box 56)
- Nicaragua (Box 56)
- Nigeria (Box 56)
- Nixon (Box 56)
- Nomenklatura (Box 56)
- Nenashev, M. (Box 56)
- Norway (Box 168)
- NTS (Box 56)
- Nuikin, Andrei (Box 56)
- Okudzhava, Bulat (Box 57)
- Oleinik, B. (Box 57)
- Orphans (Box 57)
- OECD (The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development) (Box 57)
- OPEC (Box 57)
- Orwell (Box 57)
- OSCE, 1995-2000 (Box 57)
- PACE, 2003-2005 (Box 57)
- Party - returning card, 1989-1990 (Box 57)
- Party conference 1988-1990 (Box 57)
- Party program 2/1998 (Box 57)
- Passport (Box 57)
- Pasternak, Boris (Box 57)
- Pavlov, Valentin (Box 57)
- Peace Corps (Box 57)
- Pechenev, Vadim (Box 57)
- Perestroika (Box 57)
- Philosophy (Box 57)
- Platonov (Box 57)
- Poland (Box 57)
- Political Consul. Council (PKS) (Box 57)
- Political prisoners (Box 57)
- Pomerantz, Grigorii (Box 57)
- Poptsov, Oleg (Box 57)
- Portugal (Box 57)
- Post-communism (Box 57)
- Potanin, Viktor (Box 57)
- Press (general) (Box 57)
- Press Low (Box 57)
- Prisons (Soviet) (Box 57)
- Pristavkin, Anatolii (Box 57)
- Prokofiev, Iurii (Box 57)
- Psychiatric hospitals (Box 57)
- Pugo, Boris (Box 57)
- Qatar (Box 58)
- Radical reforms (Box 58)
- Rassadin, Stanislav (Box 58)
- Razumovsky, G. P. (Box 58)
- Reagan, Ronald (Box 58)
- Red Cross (Box 58)
- Republicans, 1994-2001 (Box 58)
- Revolution (Box 58)
- Romania (Box 58)
- Grigorii Romanov (Box 58)
- Rozov, Viktor (Box 58)
- Rodionov, general (Box 58)
- Russia and Autonomous Republics, 1990-1994 (Box 58)
- Russia and Autonomous Republics, 1994-2000 (Box 58)
- Russia and Other republics, 1994 (Box 58)
- Russia and Other republics, 1994-1997 (Box 59)
- RSFSR Writers Union Plenum, 1989-1990 (Box 59)
- Rubtsov, Nikolai (Box 59)
- Riurikov, D. (Box 59)
- Rumiantsev, Oleg, 1990-1992 (Box 59)
- Rus' (party) (Box 59)
- Rybakov, Anatolii (Box 59)
- Ryzhkov, Nikolai (Box 59)
- Samizdat (Box 59)
- Shafarevich, Igor, 1991-1993 (Box 59)
- Shafranik, Iurii (Box 59)
- Shaimiev, Mintimer, 1999-2001 (Box 59)
- Shakhnazarov, Georgii (Box 59)
- Shakhnazaron, Karen (Box 59)
- Shakhrai, Sergei, 1991-1993 (Box 59)
- Shakhrai, Sergei, 1994-1996 (Box 60)
- Shakirov, Raf (Box 60)
- Shamanov, Vladimir, 2000-2001 (Box 60)
- Shamil', Imam (Box 60)
- Shantsev, Valerii (Box 60)
- Shaposhnikov, 1991-1992 (Box 60)
- Sharandid, Iurii (Box 60)
- Sharansky, Natan (Box 60)
- Shatalin, Stanislav (Box 60)
- Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, 1992-1994 (Box 60)
- Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, 1994-1999 (Box 60)
- Sorokina, Svetlana (Box 60)
- Soskovets, Oleg (Box 60)
- Soslambekov, Iusup (Box 60)
- Sotsialisticheskaia Partiia (Box 60)
- South Caucasus (Box 60)
- South Ossetiia (Box 60)
- Tajikistan, 1998-2003 (Box 61)
- Tendriakov, Vladimir (Box 61)
- Terrorism (Box 61)
- Theater, Soviet (Box 61)
- Third wave - emigration (Box 61)
- Timofeev, Lev (Box 61)
- Tiraspol (Box 61)
- Tolstaya, Tatjana (Box 61)
- Tolstoy, Aleksei (Box 61)
- Trans-Caucasus Federation (Box 61)
- Trotski, Lev (Box 61)
- Trubin, Nikolai (Box 61)
- Tsipko, Aleksandr, 1989-1993 (Box 61)
- Vasiliev, Boris (Box 61)
- Venezuela (Box 61)
- Vietnam (Box 61)
- Vneshekonombank (Box 61)
- Voinovich (Box 61)
- Volskii, Arkadii (Box 61)
- Volkogonov, Dmitri (Box 61)
- Voronov, Iuri (Box 61)
- Voznesensky, Andrei (Box 61)
- V.P. (Samizdat) (Box 61)
- Vysotsky, Vladimir (Box 61)
- Western European Union (Box 61)
- Workers (Box 61)
- Wroters' Union (Box 61)
- World Bank, 1995-1998 (Box 61)
- World Bank, 1999-2001 (Box 61)
- World Criminal Court (Box 61)
- World Trade Organization, 1994-2003 (Box 61)
- Yemen (Box 61)
- Youth - Soviet (Box 61)
- Zagladin (Box 61)
- Zaikov, Lev (Box 61)
- Zamiatin (Box 61)
- Zakharov, Vasilii (Box 61)
- Zaslavskaya, Tatjana (Box 61)
- Zhukov, Georgii (Box 61)
- Zionism (Box 61)
- Zinoviev, Aleksandr (Box 61)
- Znamia, journal (Box 61)
- South Ossetiia (Box 62)
- Gelman, Aleksandr (Box 62)
- Gelman, Marat (Box 62)
- Genocide in Russia (Box 62)
- Genshtab (Box 62)
- Geology (Box 62)
- Geopolitics (Box 62)
- "Georgievtsy" (Box 62)
- Gerashchenko, Viktor (Box 62)
- Gerber, Alla (Box 62)
- Gerstenmaier, C (Box 62)
- Gessen, Masha (Box 62)
- Gevorkian, Natalia (Box 62)
- Gidaspov, B. (Box 62)
- Ginsburg, Aleksandr (Box 62)
- Girenko - Nationalities Dept. (Box 62)
- GKChP (Box 62)
- GKO (Box 62)
- Gladikin, A (Box 62)
- Glasnost Foundation (Box 62)
- Glaz'ev, Sergei, 1993-2003 (Box 62)
- Goriacheva, Svetlana (Box 62)
- Gordievskii, Oleg (Box 62)
- Gordin, Iakov (Box 62)
- Gosplan (Box 62)
- Goskomstat (Box 62)
- Goskorporatsiia (Box 62)
- Gossluzhba (Box 62)
- Gossovet (Box 62)
- Govorukhin, Stanislav (Box 62)
- GPU (Glavnoe Politicheskoe Upravlenie) (Box 62)
- Grachov, Pavel, General (Box 62)
- Grachow, Andrei (Box 62)
- Grafova, Lidiia (Box 62)
- Grain (Box 62)
- Granin, Daniil (Box 62)
- Grazhdanskoe deistvie (Box 62)
- Grazhdanskii Forum (Box 62)
- Greens (Box 62)
- Gusinskii, Vladimir, 2000-2004 (Box 62)
- Gutseriev, Mikhail (Box 62)
- Gustov, Vadim (Box 62)
- Gutionov, Pavel (Box 62)
- Gypsies (Box 62)
- Hackers (Box 62)
- Hague War Crimes (Box 62)
- Handicapped (Box 62)
- Hard currency (Box 62)
- Harvest (Box 62)
- Heads of Administrations (Box 62)
- Health, 1988-1995 (Box 62)
- Human rights, 1994-2006 (Box 63)
- Humor (Box 63)
- Hunger (Box 63)